[Music]
hmm
good afternoon all of you as we all know
the insurance industry is a deep pocket
industry
and said that it is one of the most
difficult industries to generate
sustainable profit growth
has been a ca for freedom's business is
no easy task
the cfos have to constantly juggle
between managing capital
and getting their lmi and again with an
increased focus on
technology and digitization over the
last few years
and with the emergence of insurance tech
there is always disclaimer
for allocating capital towards them now
against this backdrop
i would like to invite some prominent
industry cfos
to understand what are their concerns
and gain valuable insights and inputs
in managing the same i would now like to
introduce the members in our panel today
the first one with us is mr bhativanan
balakrishnan the cfo of idbi federal
life insurance company
mr mativaran comes with more than 23
years of progressive experience
in finance and operations management
both startups
as well as established organizations in
the life insurance sector
prior to joining idbi federal in 2007 he
had successful stints in corporate
finance and operations
with amy smart life and reliance life
the next uh one on our panel is the
cedric fernandes
the cf of quarterback life insurance
company
mrs over two decades of work experience
most of which has been with the cortex
group he joined kodak madra old mutual
life insurance in 2000
in his immediate prior assignment he was
the accounts functions in the
he played a vital role in establishing
processes and systems
and continual best practices
the next one on our panel is mr mirajit
mukherjee this year future
insurance company ranjeet has been the
cfo future generally for close to five
years
in his previous role he was associated
with tata ideal insurance company
limited
and last but not least the ca
hello our general life insurance company
mr
chartered accountants with
the control of experience and associated
with isil
but for close decades i say i say
embarked
and he has the extension of icici
lombard
the first indian non-life insurance
company listed
so welcome all gentlemen
as we know the overall focus for the
insurance industry is to get the
operating model going
thereby throwing varied lingeries
now in this context while the overall
blueprint
to achieve the same is laid down by the
ceo of the strategy council for a
company
the role of cfo is quite critical to
implement
monitor those priorities and then help
the organization to get to that optimum
operating model
now to reach that optimum operating
model i'm sure there are some challenges
to achieve the same
so let me start by asking gopal you know
this question
as we can see that insure tech had
already
started coming up as a dis disrupter
with
distribution channels and we are seeing
shift from the traditional physical
channels to digital channels
with this pandemic the tradition channel
has
been further challenged isn't it so what
do you see the impact of the same on the
insurance
so if you look at the operating model of
the non-life insurance sector ours is a
sector which has got a mixed bag
we get to experience certain products
which fundamentally gets
sold largely in a physical format
and equally there are certain product
lines
which can kind of take through the path
of
the digital way of selling
but the way we would look at is in terms
of the approach that one would want to
take on the operating model
it kind of fundamentally changes gears
particularly in the kovit 19 situation
as all of us has experienced that
obviously physical reach was not
definitely possible
and hence one had to significantly
calibrate
on what would be the way of still
continuing to run the businesses
in the way how you would want to have
seen it operating
now in that context i think companies
which have been kind of successful
in doing two three things in managing
this entire
transition is one put in place
a de-risk model which is to say that you
don't have
all of your eggs in one basket and so
that
in the event if anything was to get
materialized then to that extent the
entire operating model gets put to test
and hence survival of the institution uh
becomes difficult so hence to that
extent i think that one of the foremost
learnings that one would want in this
scenario is significantly look at a
degress
model and to that extent something or
the other clicks in
at times of adversity so that's one
the second is i think there is a need
for you to be
continuing to maintain prudence because
there are two parts that
organizations can take particularly the
since we are talking of in the insurance
context
we all know for the fact that the levels
of underpenetration of the market
is quite significant and the opportunity
for growth is
equally humongous now there are paths
that one could take
in terms of significantly only riding
the revenue objective
and in the process possibly losing sight
from a bottom line perspective and in
these
testing times i think it again becomes
extremely important from an operating
model
standpoint to again have a fine balance
between continuing to stay focused on
driving the revenue
opportunity that one sees but equally
trying to stay focused
in so far as the contribution to bottom
line objective is concerned as well
and in that regard when you look at it
from an isis a lombard perspective
i think not just in these current times
but even over the years
the operating model that we have largely
advocated is to significantly focus on
profitable growth as a theme
in order to run the businesses and
equally i think the fact that i spoke
about
uh when arvind you spoke about insure
tech
and digitization i think again as a
company
we have been early adopters of digital
and when we look at
digital it's not just about with respect
to sourcing of policies
we look at digital across the three
spectrums of
sourcing claims management and even when
you look at
internal processes so that's how we have
looked at the overall
environment in the current times in
terms of how you can look at
shaping up and or operating models
that's the initial comments that i would
live with
uh thanks gopal thanks thanks for those
inputs
really just gives a broadcast in terms
of you just don't look at digitization
or a distribution channel only from a
sales side but from an overall
transformation to the company as a whole
so yes
that absolutely makes sense for an
overall operating model to work for an
insurance industry
now taking cue from that uh
cedric i would like to ask you this
question i mean
need of the hour and investment in right
technology you know has helped companies
a lot during this pandemic
now considering that the insurance
industry was one of the essential
industries
which had to keep working during the
pandemic
how do you visualize the increased use
of technology
and you know it's likely impact on
insurance companies as a whole what are
your thoughts on that
said
arvind thanks for the question i think
was a very good question in the
current uh times i think so uh insurance
companies general both life i think so
recognize the need of
technology and digitization data
analytics
uh because that gives you good impetus
across
distribution channels your operational
processes risk processes
uh but in this time of kovaid
it has actually accelerated the entire
process okay
and uh this year has been a challenge
for us
but i think so in this year none of the
insurance companies would have cut their
expenditure on digitization or going
digital
because if you look at the part of the
overall strategy of the business
till the challenges or the operations
process risk processes
as a investment for the future
i would see that all insurance companies
would significantly invest in this year
this year maybe slightly prudently
because uh it is
the initial year but going forward the
next five years i think so they
spend on uh investments in the digital
channels and i t is going to
considerably increase
and uh the need the reason for that is
also if you look during this covet time
uh the customers are actually the ones
who are asking for it customers have
gone online they have
felt the need of insurance they want to
buy it like any other product
and the regulator has recognized it if
you look at it the recent circulars from
the irda where they have come about with
a lot of uh
relaxation in terms of getting wet
signatures and
allowing things to be done online i
think so these two signals which you get
from a customer and a regulator in
addition to your own push
has actually uh you know made it i think
so
it's not an option for insurance
companies it's a matter of how fast do
you want to go
so i think so uh in these times
while we have to be prudent on other
costs i.t and digital is being a
significant part of you can say the
strategy
there will be a substantial investment
going now and forward in this entire
in the space of insurance that is how i
see it going ahead because
digital while the initial cost may be
high it is one of the avenues which
allows you to reduce the overall cost of
distribution or
production or control and ultimately
insurance companies are looking at the
overall reducing the cost
so that they can give a better product
to the customer in the long run
so i think so that journey has begun it
has only got accelerated during the
current year
yeah thanks now that is what i have to
say
no aesthetic absolutely insightful and
again building up on that whole
point in terms of how the industry is
going to pan out
or change in a big way the necessary
investment required in digitization and
technology
i'm sure there there is going to be a
challenge
in terms of how do we manage that and
coming to this uh
you know taking a cue from this uh
miranda i would like to ask you a
question
is to say that with availability of
technology
do you see a change in the consumer
preference
or do you see a change in the product
mix
which you need to cater to in the future
what are your thoughts on that
thanks so uh let me segregate this
question into two parts
arvind uh ludwig has re-emphasized the
point and his gopal has re-emphasized
the point
we had to accelerate the the investments
into it because
without it you wouldn't have survived
the pandemic and most insurance
companies have very invested very
heavily due in this phase
i however have still won viewers
especially from
today the customer still wants a
face-to-face meeting
and as much as we want to wish away this
issue remember that the customer is
investing
for i'm not talking of non-life non-life
being a one-year or a two-year product
can still
have you know online complete but for a
non a life insurance company the
customer is investing for almost a 10 to
15 year horizon
and our personal experiences have been
that as much as we want to
be as digital as always and especially
with us we
we don't have a bank partner and so what
happens is that our proprietary
distribution is our prime
source of revenue so customers have said
very well we are more than willing to
tie up or do business with you
but at the end of the day you please
come and meet us
and in person still you know do the
fulfillment of the deal so the point is
that
digital has got accelerated without a
shadow doubt because of the
condemning but i can't wish away the
fact that
a face-to-face meeting especially for uh
for life insurance business would
continue to play as a very significant
part that's the first part of my answer
the second part of the answer is you
know
arvin what's happening is that
thankfully
uh you know we we are most of the
the financial services business are very
regulated
and so and especially with the insurance
companies because they don't have to
take too much of leverage other than
some of the larger ones uh customers
have a lot of especially for life
insurance companies
have a lot of a faith in in the system
in india
on on life insurance because after bank
deposit that's the most preferred
product
and what we're increasingly noticing is
that customers
obviously because of the pandemic has
shifted very strict significantly to
terms health etc
but we still see a major uptake in the
guaranteed savings products in a very
very significant way that continues to
be
a very big source of revenue as we go
along
uh bank bank bank promoted companies
still have ulip in a very big way
but uh what we're noticing is that the
customers still prefer a lot of savings
now coupled with the fact that they want
a lot of uh
protection business yeah that's my day
okay uh thanks so you know
to achieve all of this i'm sure whether
the right technology or to cater
uh to those consumer preferences you
know getting the right skill set
is always a challenge so mr mathew and i
would just like to ask you
you know with the likes of artificial
intelligence large amounts of data
you know how is the need for physical
workforce evolved and
how do you see the availability of
relevant skill staff for the insurance
industry in the future
what are your thoughts on that sir yeah
thanks arvind uh
before before answering this uh question
uh
on the operating model uh related
actually
as a cfo we are all challenging what
should be the right uh
you know operating model in the current
uh pandemic crisis
is a critical uh answer so
so so we are all you know facing the
challenges like you know what should be
the right operating model in the current
scenario
how do we you know go about on the
business group the availability of the
data to make the
you know a different scenario uh based
planning and budgetary planning for
multiple rounds of
discussions that has become really
challenging in the current
scenario so coming to a question on the
the artificial intelligence and the
digital transformation
as cedric's uh mentioned before
the digital journey has already been
there in the insurance
companies for a couple of years it has
been accelerated now in the current
pandemic crisis so to meet the
even the regulator has taken uh several
steps to
ease the uh the compliance and the uh
regulatory requirements from that
perspective
uh yes it is a challenge for us to meet
the complaints and the sexual
requirements
from the uh current environment and
with respect to the uh the regulatory uh
related
one of the important uh uh regulatory
change which
which is actually you know good for this
current center use the
regulatory sandbox regulations which
talks about you know
to promote the development via
experimentation
facilitate innovation and encourage
digital journey is is an important
regulation
which all insurance companies should
make use of
[Music]
these regulations to do to to innovate
and
to bring in more automation into the
process
whether it is an operational processes
or business processes or financial
processes
to bring in such kind of
digital is is is important that's the
need of the
heart today and and and and
and the question specific question on
availability you know the skill the
resources for
managing this yes this has been a
challenge
for us uh because people uh the most of
the resources are work from in a remote
place
not meeting each other for so many
months and days
getting the uh meeting these regulatory
requirements and timelines with
a lot of accuracy has been a challenge
for the cfos
in the current scenario yes we need to
have you know people
trained and on the new set of skill
they should be used to you know how to
work from room effectively
for the organization sure
uh but uh thanks absolutely mr mathewan
for your thoughts uh
you know and meranjeet may be asking
this question uh
to you specifically because you touched
upon that point in terms of
changing environment and the risk being
prevalent you know
all of us i mean it's a no-brainer that
yes the pandemic has plunged india into
reception uh
you know recession we have seen um you
know
a good enough q to deep
[Music]
but is it a sign of recovery and can we
say that the worst is behind us
or whether the scars i mean nobody knows
i mean the future is out there for all
of us
but in such an environment your thoughts
on this
yeah so let me make it an
industry specific issue and a company
specific issue
so i must say the regulator has been
quite proactive
so first let me not only talk of the
insurance regulator i think sebi
because some of the uh our other
companies are listed some of the
insurance companies are listed so cb is
trying their best to
support in this environment i think the
insurance regulator has also
tried to support us in this environment
and and
what they're trying to do is accelerate
the approval process that we
generally put up to whether a product
for any process that we are changing
and most important is that we've changed
we've seen a very significant change in
in which they're trying to reach out to
companies
really to ask them whether they need any
specific help
in our particular case we needed an
approval
for um an infusion for debt and i must
thank the regulator for being very very
proactive in in supporting
because you know in these times
especially all of us working from home
and and almost having uh no physical
interaction with one another and not
getting a chance to meet the regulator i
think the regulators have been very very
supportive
and i say not only the insurance
regulator if you relate to it the
banking regulator
who's almost at the reserve bank a
governor almost comes on
a television every every two three
months and and lists various schemes
that they're offering
it's ab has done very a lot of things to
support
and the insurance regulator obviously
that they we relate to them
they've been very very supportive i
think the best bit is that they've been
reaching out to companies and to the
industry
asking that whether you need any support
from our side and i think
all kudos to them
sure great great great
you know not consolidation has been the
mantra for the insurance industry in
general uh
you know and over there you know asset
liability management or capital
management they just become priority
tasks for any cfo for insurance company
so
what do you think maybe gopal you might
give that answer first because you've
gone through
an acquisition yourself what do you
think
the mantra is is consolidation the theme
going forward
and what are your thoughts on that in
general
that's a good question uh arvind because
you always find opportunities and
adversities right that's what it's
always said
yeah and that's how you kind of look at
possible scenarios emerging
so let me just again put it in the
context of the industry i think
one of the things that i mentioned
originally was the path that
institutions take
right particularly we are in the
business of let's say particularly
let's say on the non-life side we are
primarily in the business of let's say
taking premiums from customers and we
obviously have an obligation to make
good those
payment of premiums in the form of
claims um as and when they were to
materialize
the beauty of the business is while
mirajit said that the terms
a term period of our policies are likely
maybe relatively shorter duration as
compared to
the life side but in so far as claims
development is concerned
there are certain businesses which kind
of fundamentally runs over relatively
longer periods of time
and hence given the uncertainty that
comes particularly with respect to
this long-term development of claims
each companies needs to be extremely
prudent
in the way they run their operations or
in the way they build their operating
model
and there have been let's say challenges
in the market
with certain participants possibly uh
trying to be
far more aggressive in so far as revenue
objectives are concerned
and possibly i'm sure they would have
had their own objective
in so so far as meeting their bottom
line targets are concerned
but in these times when i said
particularly during
uh this stressful scenarios uh even the
preferences of the customers start to
significantly shift to
players which are relatively carrying a
stronger brand
which have got a better balance sheet
and at the same time
who are equally kind of reasonably
comfortable in so far as
solvency or capital adequacy positions
are concerned
and in this backdrop is when and these
are also times
when let's say the ability of and the
promoters
or the investors who are backing the
companies
they may also not necessarily have deep
pockets of
being able to continue to make
investments over a relatively longer
period of time
and it is in that context is where
possibly you get to see
uh opportunities emerging and that's how
uh i mean when you rightly mentioned
that we did make an
announcement of an acquisition as we
speak uh it is how this is
that's how we are kind of looked at this
opportunity uh this was something that
um isis alumni had kind of reached out
uh to bharti axa in terms of the
opportunity that we looked at
and clearly i think there are various
filters that we would obviously look at
before looking at any transaction
and the beauty of the transaction that
we currently announced
i think kind of check boxed most of the
things that we would look for in a
transaction which is
a strong governance good management
in terms of their disclosures reserving
practices
i think they were all kind of fitting in
the
right checkboxes i think it's just that
the opportunity of the business would
have kind of played through over a
relatively longer period of time
and that's exactly where i think from an
icc lombard perspective
on a merged basis we would be able to
realize
some of those synergies from a long term
standpoint
but yes your point is absolutely right
uh where there are in these times you
get to see
companies unfortunately uh maybe who may
not be necessarily having the desired
capital for which they will be able to
continue to maintain uh
infusion momentum or for the matter of
fact the players who would not have been
let's say relatively prudent in so far
as let's say the underwriting practices
are concerned
you get to see definitely opportunities
of consolidation and what we have seen
is maybe
few examples of consolidation in the
non-life insurance space
but my sense is over the next maybe
three to five years
time horizon we would definitely get to
see far more opportunities
emerging and and there are and players
who are as i said
relatively having a strong brand a very
good
balance sheet and a relatively better
solvency position
i'm sure they would all be kind of
looking for opportunities
as and when they arise that's how we
have looked at the consolidation space
sure uh you know maybe tempting as an
accountant
all my life to ask this question to
cedric uh you know there is ifrs 17
which is coming up on the horizon
it's a it's a game changing standard
there is also rbc which is there on the
minds of the regulator
how soon ascetic you think or what
impact
do you think will these
initiatives matter to the insurance
industries and whole and how do you see
the regulators playing the role in this
yeah i think so another good question
arvin
i think so ifrs my own view ifrs 117 is
going to change
the way in which people look at
insurance companies
because uh of two three reasons one of
one of it is that
uh historically we are always showing
you the balance sheet and the p
l of what has come through the p l and
therefore it's only the net worth
but ifr is supposed to try and capture
the entire embedded value on onto your
financial accounts
and also does a lot of sensitivity and
disclosure so that you can read and
understand the numbers
which was not which is not there
currently uh
two it is putting the casting the owners
on the
the cfo because ifrs 117 is finally an
accounting standard
and uh although there is a lot of actual
input on the side
but finally certification of those
numbers and an audit today which we rely
on only a certificate in the actuary
is going to move to a cfo role and an
audit role so i think so
these two in combination puts the owners
on the cfos
to basically understand the numbers get
data
and also validate everything what is
coming through
the embedded value in the on the
finances
uh i think so today any insurance
company
the key to look at is the embedded value
is done by
referred to the financials only so
i think so it is bound to happen it's
only a question of timing
internationally the date is
maybe 2023 because of the pandemic maybe
there would be
maybe a slight delay here and there but
uh private insurance companies
like us somewhere through the to the
holding company
or through uh pressure whenever we are
listed
will make us actually get into an ifrs
rank of transformation sooner than we
expect
so i don't think so while the government
may make it mandatory i don't know
the date today it's going maybe in line
with the international deadline
but uh i would think so we will be
compelled as insurance companies
to do it for the purposes of our own
valuation because the moment it gets
adopted in europe
and for any listing purpose any any kind
of capital which we need
i think so there's no option we'll have
to do a financials to
117 and we will have to do we will get a
valuation we'll get a embedded value
and uh basically a valuation will be
based on those numbers
so i think is the big step uh for the
cfos office puts a lot of owners
because understanding of the entire
actual principles involved
is good but i think so our time has come
when we have to we
where we have reached that stage it
gives us a great opportunity
because as a as a as finance
professionals we are getting
now into a complete insight into the
actual way of how do i estimate the
future
and there will be a lot of owners on the
cfo's office to
to ensure that all numbers are
understood well and explainable
uh and i think so this in the future
will play a very key role
in understanding the finance the future
of any insurance company
so i think so it's a welcome step and i
don't think so it will take a lot of
time it is not in the distant future
while there may be some deadlines which
the government may
extend but i think so as individual
entities as we are
we'll be compelled to do it sooner than
later i think
that is my view great great study
i think that sets the tone
you know thank you uh thank you all
we have that limited time in terms of
you know trying to close our section but
uh i will just
probably take this opportunity to say
that thank you for your time gentlemen i
know this
session has been extremely enlightening
uh
now hosting an insurance submit
electronically indicates in more than
one ways right the shift in the way we
see the things evolving right that
itself tells us
lots of things to all of us so the
insurance industry has also seen the
rise of technology usage
uh insure tech is becoming a regular
part of our dictionary as we say
and uh last but not the least you know i
foreseen or
whichever is the new regulation which is
going to probably change the way
financials will look like
looks to be a reality if not immediately
but in the near future
and it's something which we can't fish
up with so you know the few
takeaways from the change in the ways of
we doing the business from my side would
be fair to summarizes
technology would play a large role in
insurance both in operations and
distribution
along with conventional skill sets
employability
of individuals would depend on agility
of the workforce to upskill themselves
with technical developments
and faced with challenging task as a cfo
whether it is lifis implementation
or whether it is implementing technology
allocating cost
uh it is a no-brainer that the insurance
business is
and will remain a vital contributor uh
to the
wheels to the economy in times to come
and this can only happen
with the constant guidance from the
regulator
in managing this changing dynamics for
the industry as a whole
so that's what i could gather from you
and thank you uh sincerely for your
valuable inputs and thoughts
it really just helps or opens your minds
uh gazing to the future and see how
you can navigate through those risks in
the changing dynamic
thanks a lot thanks thank you so much
and uh request everyone to stay safe
at this time thank you okay thanks erwin
thanks
thanks thanks